imshealth.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

IMS Health is committed to protecting the online privacy of our visitors' personally identifiable information. To better protect your privacy online, this statement explains our online information practices at this Website.

**What Information We Collect and How We Use It**

We may collect the following types of personally identifiable information at this website: name, address, e-mail, and telephone number. We also may collect additional information, including credit card and other billing information, when you register to purchase products and services available through our network of websites.

We use this information to enable you to purchase our products and services on-line, to enable delivery of products and services to you on-line, to process payments for purchase of products and services on-line, to respond to your requests, which include providing you with our product and service updates, to enable you to participate in surveys or questionnaires posted on our website, and to provide you with opportunities to learn about other products, programs, or services that we believe may be of interest to you. Generally speaking, we do not share personally identifiable information with unrelated third parties who are not covered by this privacy statement without your prior permission.

_Careers_

__At the Careers section of our site, visitors can submit resume information, enabling individuals to express their interest in becoming part of the IMS Health team. To provide you with these services, we have contracted with Workday, which processes your information according to instructions from IMS Health. Our Privacy Statement does not cover Workday's collection and use of your information in connection with this service. For more information on Workday's privacy practice, consult its privacy policy at [www.workday.com](http://www.workday.com/).

_E-mail_

__IMS Health and/or its affiliates occasionally send e-mail and promotional notifications to users of its network of sites, products and services. IMS Health may also engage third-party vendors to act on our behalf and administer our e-mail services, which would require disclosure of the e-mail address you provided to IMS Health to such vendors, acting on our instructions. We may use this information in the aggregate to analyze the effectiveness of our e-mail and promotional notifications and site usage, either by IMS Health, or through our third-party e-mail provider. If you wish to discontinue receipt of e-mail or promotional notifications from IMS Health, please contact the IMS Health customer service center at  [optout@imshealth.com](http://www.imshealth.com/portal/site/imshealth/menuitem.18c196991f79283fddc0ddc01ad8c22a/?vgnextoid=48b5e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&vgnextchannel=48b5e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&vgnextfmt=default#), with the word “remove” in the subject line to be removed from our promotional mailing lists, or follow the “unsubscribe” instructions at the end of the e-mail or promotional notification.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information_

__We may collect certain non-personally identifiable information about our visitors when you visit many of our webpages, such as the type of browser you are using (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using, (e.g., Windows 2000 or Mac OS), and the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., America Online, Earthlink).

We use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our site and to enable us to better personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze site usage.

_Legal Process and Outside Parties_

__We may disclose information we maintain in response to legal proceedings, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may transfer information about you if we are acquired by or merged with another company.

**Cookies**

To enhance your experience with our site, we may use “cookies.” Cookies are text files that may be stored in your computer's browser (i.e. in memory for the duration of the active session) or on the user's hard drive by the software we use on our network of sites to store your preferences and perform other administrative functions. We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the user experience, create personalized offerings, and improve the content and offerings on our network of sites. Some of our software vendors use cookies for purposes that may be different from those stated in our Privacy Statement, and our Privacy Statement does not cover our software vendors' collection and use of your information by way of cookies in connection with our network of websites. For more information on the use of cookies on our network of websites, please e-mail us at [webmaster@imshealth.com](http://www.imshealth.com/portal/site/imshealth/menuitem.18c196991f79283fddc0ddc01ad8c22a/?vgnextoid=48b5e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&vgnextchannel=48b5e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&vgnextfmt=default#), identify the application, product or service you wish to know more about, and a link to that software vendor's privacy notice will be provided.

**Links**

Our network of sites contain links to other websites whose information practices may be different from ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties, and our Privacy Statement does not cover activities occurring at other websites.

**Security**

We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent unauthorized access to the information that we collect online.

**Terms of Use**

This Privacy Statement is part of, and subject to, the Terms and Conditions applicable to products, services and activities available through www.imshealth.com.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this statement or would like more information on our privacy practices, please contact us at [webmaster@imshealth.com](http://www.imshealth.com/portal/site/imshealth/menuitem.18c196991f79283fddc0ddc01ad8c22a/?vgnextoid=48b5e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&vgnextchannel=48b5e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&vgnextfmt=default#).
